So it's business time right now.
이제 시작이에요
We are going to build a Rag pipeline to estimate the price of products, drawing on context for similar
제품 가격을 추정하는 래그 파이프라인을 구축할 겁니다 훈련 데이터셋에 있는 유사한
products that we have in our training dataset.
제품의 컨텍스트를 참고해서요
Uh, and so we are right here.
그래서 여기 왔어요
Day 2.3 building a Rag pipeline with GPT four mini.
둘째 날이죠 3번 GPT4 미니로 래그 파이프라인을 만들어요
Uh, we're going to go pretty quickly today through a lot of code.
오늘은 많은 코드를 빠르게 다룰 거예요
So bear with me then.
그럼 조금만 참아주세요
Remember the trick is to come back, run the code yourself and get a good sense of what's going on.
Get it의 비결은 직접 코드를 실행해 어떤 상황인지 파악하는 거예요
So we do some imports, we log in as usual, and then we, uh, connect with OpenAI.
그래서 가져오기를 하고 평소처럼 로그인해서 오픈라이에 접속했어요
Um, and it's using the fact that we've set the OpenAI API key.
OpenAI API 키를 설정했다는 사실을 이용하고 있어요
We're going to load in the test data set.
테스트 데이터 세트를 로드할 거예요
Now, we don't need to load in the training data set because we'll be using the chroma data store for
훈련 데이터 세트를 로드할 필요는 없어요 크로마 데이터 저장소를 사용할
that.
거니까요
All right.
좋아요
So here's a function make context.
함수 만들기 컨텍스트가 있어요
We're going to use this function to produce the context that we're going to send GPT four mini that
이 함수를 이용해 컨텍스트를 생성할 겁니다 GPT for 미니를 보내 사용할 수 있는
tells it about similar products that it could use.
비슷한 제품에 대해 알려주는 거죠
So we're going to say to provide some context, here are some other items that might be similar to the
컨텍스트를 제공하라고 할 거예요 여러분이 추정해야 하는 것과 유사한 다른 항목들이
one you need to estimate.
여기 있어요
And then do you remember this zip construct that allows us to iterate through two different lists together.
압축 파일 생성기 기억하시나요? 두 개의 다른 리스트를 반복할 수 있게 해주죠
So we're going to collect similar and price from iterating through the similars and prices that are
통과된 비슷한 가격과 비슷한 가격의 반복을 통해 비슷한 가격과 비슷한 것을 수집하는
passed in.
거죠
And then we're going to add in a message there's a potentially related product similar with this price.
그런 다음 메시지를 추가합니다 이 가격과 관련 있을 가능성이 있는 제품이 있다고요
I'll execute this in just a second.
잠시 후에 실행할게요
So you see what it actually looks like.
어떤 모습인지 볼 수 있죠
But then just as we've done in the past, I'm making this function messages for and it takes an item,
그런데 과거에 했던 것처럼 이 함수 메시지를 만들고 항목을 하나 가져가고
it takes things similar to it and it takes prices and it's going to build that standard list of dicts
비슷한 걸 가져가고 가격을 가져가고 표준 독감 목록을 만듭니다 우리가
that we know so, so well.
잘 아는 거죠
There's going to be a system message which is going to be just the same one we've used before.
시스템 메시지가 있을 겁니다 전에 사용했던 것과 동일한 거죠
You estimate price of items, reply only with the price we're going to add in the context.
물품의 가격을 추정하고 컨텍스트에 추가할 가격으로만 응답하세요
We're going to add in the stuff that we just built right here.
방금 만든 걸 추가할게요
And then we're going to say.
그리고 이렇게 말해요
And now the question for you.
이제 질문할게요
And now this is basically exactly the same as we used before when we called GPT four back in week six
이건 기본적으로 우리가 전에 사용했던 것과 같습니다 6주 차에 GPT 4를 호출했을 때요 파이프라인을
when we built that pipeline.
구축했을 때요
So the thing to notice here is that we're doing this Rag pipeline ourself without Lang chain.
여기서 주목할 건 랭 체인 없이 랙 파이프라인을 하고 있다는 거죠
And it's actually not that hard.
사실 그렇게 어렵지도 않아요
Lang chain gave us a nice little abstraction on top with with a few simple objects.
랭 체인은 간단한 개체 몇 개로 추상화를 제공했어요
And I remember going on about how it was just like one line of code or something to do it, but it's
코드 한 줄이면 된다고 했던 게 기억나네요 하지만 직접
not that much more just to do it ourselves.
하기엔 그리 많지 않아요
Particularly now that you understand what's going on under the hood and you know how to call llms and
특히 지금은 보닛 밑에서 무슨 일이 일어나는지 알고 llms를 호출하는 법과
you know how to look up similar objects and so on.
유사한 개체들을 찾아내는 법 등을 알고 있으니까요
Um, it becomes relatively straightforward.
비교적 간단해요
Uh, so, um, hopefully this is not going to be too, uh, um, difficult, but let's keep going.
너무 힘들지 않았으면 좋겠네요 계속 가보죠
Um, so we're going to, um.
그래서 갈 거예요
Collect our chroma.
채도를 채취할게요
Um, and once more, I've done this again, haven't I?
또 이런 말을 했네요
I deleted the cell where I defined the DB variable.
DB 변수를 정의했던 핸드폰을 지웠어요
It should be products Underscore.
제품 밑줄로 해야죠
Vector store.
벡터 스토어요
Some possibly hard word to spell.
어려운 단어일 거예요
There we go.
됐어요
And now run that again.
다시 실행해요
Fine.
좋아요
So we've now we're looking in the products collection in our vector data store.
이제 벡터 데이터 저장소에서 제품 컬렉션을 살펴봤죠
Um okay.
알았어요
And so we're now getting to the meat of the whole thing.
이제 본론으로 들어가는 거죠
So we're going to have a method, a function description that's going to take an item.
메서드, 함수 설명이 있습니다 항목을 취할 거예요
And it's going to strip out from that item the stuff that we don't care about.
해당 항목에서 우리가 관심 없는 걸 걸러내죠
So basically we'll take the prompt and we're going to take out this.
기본적으로 프롬프트를 가져다가 이걸 빼낼 거예요
How much does it cost to the nearest dollar.
1달러까지 얼마나 들까요?
And we're going to then uh, ignore everything that comes after price is dollars.
가격 이즈 달러 다음에 나오는 건 다 무시할 거예요
Let me show you exactly what's going on here.
정확히 어떤 건지 보여드릴게요
Uh, so if I have a quick look at my first training data point.
제 첫 훈련 데이터 포인트를 잠깐 살펴볼게요
Oops.
이런, 미안해요
Sorry.
미안해요
What have I done?
내가 무슨 짓을 한 거죠?
Test the first test data point.
첫 번째 테스트 데이터 포인트를 테스트하세요
We're not looking at training data anymore.
훈련 데이터는 더 이상 안 봐요
The first test data point is this the repair kit for Ford, blah blah, blah, blah, blah with a price
첫 번째 데이터 포인트는 포드의 수리 키트 어쩌고저쩌고 가격도 적혀
on it.
있네요
Uh, if we look at its prompt, you'll see that that that's got all of this gubbins in there with the
프롬프트를 보면 여기 잡동사니들이 있는 게 보이실 겁니다 가격과 상단에
price and the question at the top.
질문이 있죠
But what I can do is I can just say describe description of test zero.
하지만 이렇게 말할 수 있어요 test 제로 설명
And what we should now get is this just the blurb without the price.
이제 가격 없는 카피만 Get up 하면 돼요
So that should be clear.
그러니 분명하죠
All right.
좋아요
Now we're going to load the model that is the sentence transformer from hugging face.
이제 얼굴을 안는 것에서 문장 변압기인 모델을 로드할게요
That gives us our simple vector encodings.
그게 간단한 벡터 인코딩을 제공하죠
It is our vectorizer.
우리 벡터라이저예요
And so this method here, this is in fact our Vectorizer function.
이 메서드는 벡터라이저 함수예요
It takes an item.
아이템이 필요해요
It it calls description on that item to turn it into text.
해당 아이템에 대한 설명을 호출해 텍스트로 바꾸죠
And it then puts it in a list and calls model dot encode.
목록에 넣고 모델 .in코드를 호출해요
Simple as that.
간단해요
And now and now we get to a function find similars.
이제 유사한 함수를 찾는 함수가 나와요
It will be given an item and it will return similar items.
항목을 받으면 비슷한 걸 반환하죠
And this, this is the some of the hardest part that Lang was doing for us before, but it's not that
랭이 전에 했던 것 중 가장 어려운 부분이지만 그렇게 어렵진 않아요
You can see what we do is we say to our collection, our chroma DB collection, I want to query this.
컬렉션에 이렇게 말하는 걸 볼 수 있어요 크로마 DB 컬렉션 이걸 쿼리 하고 싶어요
These are the query embeddings.
쿼리 삽입이죠
This is it's going to be based on this, uh, the vector that we will pass in.
우리가 통과할 벡터를 기반으로 하는 거예요
We do have to turn that into a floating point number from being a numpy array.
nomp 배열에서 부동 소수점 수로 바꿔야 해요
That's uh, from being a numpy float 32.
그건 바보 32인조라서 그래요
You have to turn them into floats, and then we have to turn it into a list instead of being a numpy
플로트로 바꿔야 합니다 그리고 목록으로 바꿔야 해요 nomp 배열이
array.
아니라요
And then you just simply say, uh, number of results and that's how many you want back.
그다음에는 결과의 수를 적으면 돼요 그게 다시 돌려받고 싶은 수죠
So you can pass in a vector as your query embedding and get back five results.
쿼리 삽입을 벡터로 전달해 5개의 결과를 get 할 수 있죠
That's all there is to it.
그게 다예요
And what we'll get back is uh, is some similars, uh, so let's just run this.
Get in get은 유사한 것들이에요. 실행해 볼게요.
So now what we can do is we can look at test number one and let's look at test number one's prompt.
이제 할 수 있는 건 테스트 1을 볼 수 있습니다 테스트 1 프롬프트를 보죠
So this is its prompt.
이게 프롬프트예요
Um how much does it cost to the nearest dollar.
얼마면 살 수 있어요?
It's a fan clutch package.
팬 클러치 패키지예요
Uh, from, um motorcraft.
모터크래프트에서 왔어요
So anyway, you get a sense.
어쨌든 감을 잡게 되죠 get it
So we can now say documents and prices are fine.
이제 문서와 가격은 괜찮다고 할 수 있죠
Find Similares from test one.
1번 테스트에서 유사점을 찾아요
We're going to call this function right here to find five similar results.
이 함수를 호출해 비슷한 결과 5개를 찾아볼게요
Let's do that.
그렇게 하죠
And now it's thinking.
이제 생각하네요
And now let's print that.
이제 프린트할게요
And here you will find five related results are potentially related products.
여기서 관련 결과가 5개 나올 거예요 관련 제품이 될 수도 있죠
And they are all potentially related product.
모두 관련 상품일 가능성이 있어요
They are all sort of fan clutchy kind of things that have various prices.
클러치 달린 물건인데 가격이 다양해요
Uh, and they do appear to be similar products at first blush.
언뜻 보면 비슷한 제품으로 보이긴 해요
Uh, so you should convince yourself, do some more testing and make sure you're comfortable that indeed
그러니 자신을 설득하고 더 테스트하고 유사한 함수를
we can call this find similar function, which is simply calling query on our Cromer collection.
찾도록 하세요 Cromer 컬렉션에 쿼리를 호출하는 거죠
And we will be able to collect similar products from our Cromer database.
크로머 데이터베이스에서 비슷한 제품을 수집할 수 있어요
It's as simple as that.
아주 간단해요
Uh, and once we've done that, we will then be able to put the final touches on our Rag data flow on
그 작업이 끝나면 랙 파이프라인에 있는 랙 데이터 흐름에 최종 손질을 할 수 있습니다
our Rag pipeline and then use that to call GPT four zero.
그걸 이용해 GPT 40을 호출하죠
And we will do that in the next video.
다음 비디오에서 보여드릴게요